

About me

Currently Ph.D. student Research Engineer at FEMTO-ST Institute. I design, fabricate and control a deformable continuum robot for middle ear surgery. With over 4 years experiences of working on different professional projects: both academic and industrial, I am looking for a job in R&D for September 2022. I learn and adapt quickly to be rapid operational.

Contacts



19 Rue de l'Epitaphe 25000 Besançon



(+33) 07 69 35 72 98



ndvanh1994@gmail.com dang.nguyen@femto-st.fr



in linkedin.com/in/dva-nguyen



linkedin.com/in/dva-nguyen/

Skills

Programming

MATLAB, Python, C++, C, Qt, Linux Xenomai

· CAD & Mesh

SolidWorks, AutoCAD, Meshlab

Simulation

GUI, Simulink, Blender

Langues

French

Professional working proficiency

English

Professional working proficiency

Vietnamese

Native language

References

Kanty Rabenorosoa

Associate Professor at FEMTO-ST (+33) 03 81 40 28 13

· Jérôme Szewczyk

Professor at Sorbonne University (+33) 01 44 27 62 41 szewczyk@isir.upmc.fr

· Yann Nguyen

ENT Surgeon at Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital (AP-HP) Professor at Sorbonne University (+33) 01 42 16 31 66 yann.nguyen@aphp.fr

Dang-Viet-Anh NGUYEN

Engineer in Smart Systems & Devices – Biomedical robotics

Experience

FEMTO-ST Institute

10/2018 - Present

MicroRobot-assisted Cholesteatoma Surgery – µRoCS project

Research Engineer - PhD Student in Biomedical Robotics

Besancon, France Topic: Hybrid Continuum Robot for Middle Ear Surgery: Design, Fabrication and Control

- ☐ Conception & design:
 - 3D reconstruction and post-processing the mesh of a patient's ear based on CT scan DICOM images using Invesalius, MeshLab, and SolidWorks.
 - Proposition of a hybrid concentric tube robot dedicated for middle ear laser surgery.
 - Modelization of the proposed robot and solving related problems (BVP, FEM, shortest path algorithm, inverse design problem) using MATLAB.
 - Simulation, visualization, and analysis of the robot behavior within the anatomy using Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) and C++.
 - Optimization of the robot's design parameters based on the robot workspace.
- - Preparing the **CAD** file using SolidWorks for fabricating the robot components.
 - Micro-Nano manufaturing the robot components and the ear 3D model including: nanoscribe 3d printing, femtoprint, electrical discharge machining, tube shape setting.
 - Lightweight and compact prototype for the integration on the otologic robot RobOtol.
- ☐ Control & programming:
 - Developing a realtime GNU/Linux operating system (using Xenomai) to control the robot via TCP/IP protocol and through an EtherCAT slave card.
 - Developing an interface using Qt Creator to operate the robot.
- ☐ Experimental validation & other tasks:
 - Measuring the position/orientation of the robot tip using AURORA Sensors.
 - Image processing for robot repeatability and laser ablation with OCT volume scan.
 - Deploying the robot within the ear phantom model and demonstrating laser ablation of the infected cells (cholesteatoma) collected from Besançon Hospital.
 - Writing technical reports and publishing research articles.
 - Participation in monthly technical meetings with scientists, surgeons and engineers in the µRoCS project team.

LCIS Laboratory - Grenoble INP - UGA Research Engineer - Graduation Project

07/2017 - 07/201802/2018 - 07/2018

Topic: Power Balancing in a DC-meshed Microgrid through Constrained Optimization

- Analysis of the weather forecast and the power consumption data.
- Modeling the transmission network of the meshed DC microgrid architecture.
- Optimization energy distribution for the load balancing problem in the transmission network using Model Predictive Control (MPC) based on the collected data.

Innovation Project Intern

01/2017 - 07/2017

Valence, France

Topic: Simulation, Control and Experimental tests on the Humusolt CE 150 helicopter system

- Modelization and control (PID, LQR, MPC) of the laboratory helicopter system.
- Testing & implementation on the system.
- Team leader.

LAVI - Distributeur Officiel d'Accessoires VDL

Industrial Engineering Intern

Topic: A mini smart water treatment station for motorhomes

- Design of a Printed Circuit Boards (PCB).
- Human Machine Interface (HMI) development.
- Sensors and Signal processing with STM32.

Nhat Tinh

07/2015 - 08/2015

Industrial Engineering Intern

- Mechanical drawing with SolidWorks.
- Electrical panel & mechanical assembly.

Teaching

SUPMICROTECH-ENSMM

10/2019 - 09/2021

Lectures and practical works for undergraduate students in automation and control.

Education

PhD in Automatic & Biomedical Robotics Université Bourgogne-Franche-Comté (UBFC) 10/2018 - Present

Engineer in Electronics, Informatics and Systems

9/2016 - 9/2018

École nationale supérieure en systèmes avancés et réseaux (Grenoble INP - ESISAR) Eiffel Excellence Scholarship Program 2016 (the French Ministry for Europe & Foreign Affairs)